Guide to the Lehigh Valley Railroad Company records, 1870-1962.
Lehigh Valley Railroad Company records, 1870-1962.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Lehigh Valley Railroad Company records, 1870-1962.
3362
Lehigh Valley Railroad Company.
6 cubic ft.
Financial records, reports, schedules and blueprints.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Financial records, reports, schedules, blueprints, and other records of railway lines in central and western New York State.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Financial records, reports, schedules, blueprints, and other records of railway lines in central and western New York State.
Collection includes financial records (bank books, cancelled checks, check stubs, account book, assessments), reports, indentures, mortgage, tickets, schedules, newspaper clippings, blueprints, and two broadsides concerning the organization, consolidation, finance, and other business matters pertaining to the Lehigh Valley Railway; Lehigh Valley Railroad; Waverly and State Line Railway; Geneva, Ithaca and Sayre Railroad; Elmira, Cortland and Northern Railroad; Geneva and Van Ettenville Railroad; Ithaca and Athens Railroad; Geneva and Sayre Railroad; Hayts Corners, Ovid and Willard Railroad; New York, Ontario and Western Railway; Buffalo and Geneva Railway; and the New York Railroad. Also, letter files from J.F. Powers and F.E. Erdman in the Division Freight Office, Geneva, N.Y., ca. 1925-1931; locomotive log book, Manchester, N.Y., 1959; blueprints of railroad crossings used for tax assessment; ledger of Lehigh Valley-owned structures; and ledger of special franchise maps.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lehigh Valley Railroad Company.; Erdman, F. E.; Powers, J. F.(James Farl), 1917-; Buffalo and Geneva Railway Company.; Elmira, Cortland and Northern Railroad Company.; Geneva and Sayre Railroad Company.; Geneva and Van Ettenville Railroad Company.; Geneva, Ithaca and Sayre Railroad Company.; Hayts Corners, Ovid and Willard Railway Company.; Ithaca and Athens Railroad Company.; Lehigh Valley Railway Company.; New York, Ontario, and Western Railway Co.; New York, Ontario, and Western Railway Co.; Waverly and State Line Railroad Company.
Subjects:
Railroads--New York (State); Railroads--Mergers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Broadsides.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- F.B. Payne, 1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- F.E. Erdman, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 2-22)
- F.E. Erdman - J.F. Powers, 1925-1928 (Box 1, Folder 23-29)
- F.E. Erdman - J.F. Powers, 1925-1930 (Box 1, Folder 30-35)
- F.E. Erdman, 1925-1931 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- F.E. Erdman - J.F. Powers, 1926-1927 (Box 2, Folder 3-11)
- J.F. Powers, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 12-19)
- J.F. Powers, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20-27)
- J.F. Powers, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- J.F. Powers, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 29-34)
- J.F. Powers, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 1-14)
- F.E. Erdman, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Auburn, NY (Box 3, Folder 16)
- City of Auburn assessment, 1930-1962 (Box 3, Folder 17-18)
- Canastota assessment, 1914-1962 (Box 3, Folder 19-20)
- Village of Cazenovia assessment, 1914-1962 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Supreme Court, Madison County, State of New York, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- City of Elmira assessment, 1930-1961 (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
- Elmira financial records, 1940-1952 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Elmira financial records, 1928-1940 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Village of De Ruyter assessment, 1914-1962 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Village of Fair Haven assessment, 1917-1957 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Village of Freeville assessment, 1914-1952 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Geneva land values, 1941-1946 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Town of Horseheads assessment, 1930-1961 (Box 3, Folder 31-32)
- Horseheads financial records, 1937-1955 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Horseheads property values (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Village of Elmira Heights valuation statement appraisal, 1927-1946 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Village of Van Etten assessment, 1914-1962 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Manchester log book (Box 3, Folder 37)
- The Waverly and State Line Railway Co., 1875-1892 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- The Waverly and State Line Railway Co., 1882-1884 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- The Waverly and State Line Railway Co., 1883-1884 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- The Waverly and State Line Railway Co., 1885-1885 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Geneva, Ithaca & Sayre Railroad Co. with Elmira, Cortland & Northern Railroad Co., 1884 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Geneva & Van Ettenvillle Railroad Co. organization papers, 1889-1890 (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
- Geneva & Van Ettenville Railroad Co. stockholders' meeting, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Geneva, Ithaca & Sayre Railroad Co., appointment of trustee of Ithaca & Athens Railroad mortgage in place of Josiah B. Williams (deceased), 1870; 1890 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Geneva & Sayre Railroad Co. miscellany, 1889-1890; 1902 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Geneva & Sayre Railroad Co. to Geneva & Van Ettenville Railroad Co., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Geneva, Ithaca & Sayre Railroad Co. report on the condition of rights of way, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Hayts Corners, Ovid & Willard Railroad Co. with Geneva, Ithaca & Sayre Railroad Co., 1882 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- New York, Ontario & Western Railroad Co. with Elmira, Cortland & Northern Railroad Co., 1884 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Pennsylvania & New York Canal & Railroad Co. & Lehigh Valley Railroad Co. with New York, Lake Erie & Western Railroad Co., 1882 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Southern Central Railroad Co., 1882; 1886 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- To Seneca Falls and Waterloo, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Buffalo & Geneva Railway Co. organization papers, 1889-1890 (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
- All New York Canal & Railroad Co. re. consolidation, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 21-24)
- Lehigh Valley legislation, 1889-1890 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Property owners along Geneva & Van Ettenville Railway, ca. 1890 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Lehigh Valley with Diven & Redfield, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Lehigh Valley to Philadelphia & Reading Railroad Co., 1892 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Lehigh Valley proposed extension to Buffalo, 1885-1889 (Box 4, Folder 29-30)
- Lehigh Valley papers, 1889-1896 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Lehigh Valley papers, 1890-1891 (Box 4, Folder 32-33)
- Lehigh Valley papers, 1892-1902 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Lehigh Valley Mortgage and Collateral Trust Deed, 1897 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Lehigh Valley General Consolidated Mortgage, 1903 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Accounts, 1890-1892 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Lehigh Valley statement of vouchers, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Train schedules and centennial pamphlet, 1934-1958 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Lehigh Valley tickets, newsclippings, 1935-1948 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Cancelled checks, 1890-1896 (Box 4, Folder 41-43)
- Bank books (2) - Diven, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Check stub books (3), 1890-1893 (Box 4, Folder 45-46)
- Account book - Geneva & Van Ettenville Railway Co., 1889-1890 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Rubber stamp - Lehigh Valley Railroad (Box 4, Folder 48)
- New York State Tax Department Assessment blueprints (Box 5)
- Land and Tax Department Record of Repairs, New York (Box 6)
- Blueprints (in roll tubes) (Box 7-8)
- Metal box labeled Lehigh Valley System (empty), Mu. 815
- Broadside - Lehigh Valley Easter Excursion to New York, Br. 5039
- Broadside - Lehigh Valley Easter Excursion to New York, Washington and Atlantic City, Br. 5040